<data:assembly name="Adjustment of Door Latch Mechanism">
  <module name="Procedure">
    <figure path="6-4-7.jpg"/>
    <instructions>
      <step>
        <instruction>Adjustment of the door latch mechanism is provided by an adjustable eye-end at the spring end of the push-rod, and an eccentric cam on the latch hook pivot pin (see Figure 6-4-7). On closure of a main wheel door with the gear extended, the latch mechanism should be checked for correct engagement by the roller on the door. Further checks to be made are as follows:</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>a. With main gear down and locked and main wheel door closed, adjust door latch mechanism to position latch hook to near vertical position.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>b. Open main wheel door. Check that drive fork of latch mechanism is sprung against stop.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>c. Apply Plasticine to inner curve of latch hook.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>d. Jack and steady aircraft (see C-12-114-000/ MF-001).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>e. Retract and lock gear up and then lower gear (see Paragraph 55).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>f. Check that Plasticine indicates that distance between inside of spigot and inner curve of latch hook is at least 11.4 mm (0.45 in.).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>g. If necessary, adjust on push-rod eye-end to obtain this clearance, repeating foregoing checks after any adjustment, and ensuring main wheel door roller enters jaws of drive fork centrally.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>h. Apply Plasticine to tip of latch hook so that Plasticine protrudes between 1.27 and 2.54 mm (0.05 and 0.1 in.) at tip.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>i. Retract gear slowly to house gear in wheel well, selecting gear DOWN immediately when gear is housed to prevent main wheel door from closing.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>j. Check by impression made on Plasticine that leg door spigot clears latch hook by at least 1.02 mm (0.040 in.).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>k. Carry out any necessary locking and ensure that eye-end of push-rod is in safety. Remove all traces of Plasticine.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>l. Lower aircraft to ground (see C-12-114-000/ MF-001) and remove jacking equipment.</instruction>
      </step>
    </instructions>
  </module>
</data:assembly>
