<data:assembly name="Door Link">
  <module name="Removal">
    <figure path="6-4-10.jpg"/>
    <instructions>
      <step>
        <instruction>a. Ensure that ground safety locking pins are installed to all three gears.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>b. Connect electrical ground power to aircraft. Open main wheel doors by operating hydraulic hand pump with ground servicing switch in port main gear bay selected to OPEN.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>c. Tag controls in cockpit to indicate that hydraulics are not to be operated.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>d. Disconnect door actuator (1) from upper lever of door link by removing cotter pin, nut, washer and bolt (2).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>e. Exerting pressure on door link to counteract loading of spring-box (8), remove nut, washer and screw (5).</instruction>
<note>Spring-box may be contained during removal by using spring-box clamp (see C-12-114-000/CS-031).</note>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>f. Permit spring-box (8) to extend and withdraw spring (9). Remove pin (6) and washers (7) to release door link from door.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>g. Disconnect female part of spring-box (8) from link by removing cotter pin, washer and pin (4). Note that two spacers (10) are located one each side of spring-box eye-end.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>h. To avoid possible damage to microswitch (12), screw microswitch out clear of door link.</instruction>
      </step>
    </instructions>
  </module>
  <module name = "Installation">
    <figure path="6-4-10.jpg"/>
    <step>
      <instruction>a. Position door link and connect to bracket (11) with bolt (3). Lockwire bolt with wire (see Figure 1-2, Item 12)</instruction>
    </step>
    <step>
      <instruction>b. Connect female part of spring-box (8) to link with pin (4), washer and cotter pin. Note that a spacer (10) is located on each side of springbox eye-end</instruction>
    </step>
    <step>
      <instruction>c. Install spring (9) to female half of spring-box (8) and assemble spring-box. Exerting pressure on door link to compress springbox, connect door link to door with pin (6) and washers (7), locating a washer each side of door link as shown. Lock pin (6) in position with screw (5), washer and nut</instruction>
      <note>Spring-box may be contained during installation by using spring-box clamp (see C-12-114-000/CS-031)</note>
    </step>
    <step>
      <instruction>d. Connect door actuator (1) to link with bolt (2), washer and nut. Note that cotter pin will be installed subsequent to actuator adjustment. Check adjustment of door actuator, adjusting as necessary (see Paragraph 22) and adjust door down microswitch (12) (see Paragraph 56). On completion, carry out all necessary locking, including installing a cotter pin to bolt (2).f. Operate gear (see Paragraph 55)</instruction>
    </step>
    <step>
      <instruction>g. Disconnect and remove ground power. Install ground safety locking pins, lower aircraft to ground (see C-12-114-000/MF-001) and remove jacking equipment</instruction>
    </step>
  </module>
</data:assembly>
