<data:assembly name="Side Stay Assembly">
  <module name="Removal">
    <figure path="6-4-4.jpg"/>
    <instructions>
      <step>
        <instruction>a. Jack and steady aircraft (see C-12-114-000/ MF-001).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>b. Connect ground power to aircraft. Open main wheel doors by operating hydraulic hand pump with ground servicing switch in port main gear bay selected to OPEN.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>c. Dissipate residual hydraulic pressure in aircraft system (see C-12-114-0B0/MF-001). Tag controls in cockpit.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>d. Disconnect side stay from leg by removing cotter pin, nut, washer, chamfered washer (9) and bolt (8).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>e. Disconnect main gear actuator (7) from side stay (see Paragraph 4) and secure actuator clear of working area.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>f. Trace uplock microswitch (17) lead, disconnect plug from receptacle, and secure clear of working area.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>g. Disconnect hydraulic lines (1 and 2) from uplock actuator (11). Cap open lines.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>h. Break lockwire, remove four bolts (6) and remove side stay complete with uplock assembly (5).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>i. If required, remove uplock assembly (5) (see Paragraph 9) and uplock actuator (11) (see Paragraph 11) and uplock microswitch (17) from uplock assembly.</instruction>
      </step>
    </instructions>
  </module>
  <module name = "Installation">
    <figure path="6-4-4.jpg"/>
    <instructions>
      <step>
        <instruction>a. Ensure that uplock assembly (5), with uplock actuator (11) and uplock microswitch (17) installed and correctly adjusted (see Paragraph 12), is installed on side stay (see Paragraph 10).</instruction>
        <note>Before fitting shaft anti-rotation devices (21 or 23), when installing a new shaft (16) or mounting block (20), or installing a side stay assembly into a replacement wing, install uplock (5) (see Paragraph 10) on shaft (16) and then position uplock (5) to properly receive uplock pin on main landing gear leg. For fitting data on fit of locking pin (21) and roll-pin (22), see Figure 6-4-4.</note>
        <warning>Heli-coil inserts shall be inspected for security and condition prior to installation of side stay bolts (6).</warning>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>b. Locate side stay assembly in position at wing mounting beam and temporarily secure mounting blocks with the four bolts (6).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>c. Check total clearance between side stay and attachment blocks and between uplock and adjacent attachment block. Clearances should be 0.305 mm (0.012 in.) maximum for the former and 0.254 to 0.381 mm (0.010 to 0.015 in.) for the latter.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>d. If either clearance is incorrect, remove side stay assembly and uplock assembly from side stay (see Paragraph 9). Install laminated shims (19) between, as applicable, the side stay and attachment blocks and/or between the two washers (15) to obtain the required clearances when side stay (with uplock assembly installed) is reinstalled. Lockwire bolts (6) in pairs on completion.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>e. Connect main gear actuator (7) to side stay (see Paragraph 5). Note that adjustment will be subsequently carried out.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>f. Connect side stay to leg with bolt (8), chamfered washer (9), washer, nut and cotter pin, locating chamfered washer under head of bolt.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>g. Connect hydraulic lines (1 and 2) to uplock actuator (11) ports.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>h. Top up hydraulic reservoir see C-12-114-000/ MF-001).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>i. Carry out precautions for a functional test of gear (see Paragraph 55).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>j. Connect uplock microswitch (17) plug to receptacle.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>k. Adjust setting of side stay in conjunction with checking adjustment of main gear actuator (see Paragraph 5); operate gear several times during the procedure to pass air in system to reservoir.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>l. During Step m, carry out the following checks and the applicable checks detailed in actuator installation (see Paragraph 5):</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>(1) Check uplock actuator (11) normal down line for leaks with 10 342 kPa (1500 psi) hydraulic pressure applied. Correct any leak.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>(2) With leg door disconnected to obtain better access and with gear retracted to point where uplock pin is about to enter the uplock jaws, take up all movement of uplock assembly in either right or left direction. Check that pin will have free access into the jaws in this position.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>(3) Repeat with movement taken up in opposite direction, the same requirement being applicable.</instruction>
        <note>NOTE The pin fouling the uplock jaws in either Step (2) or (3) indicates excessive wear necessitating replacement of uplock.</note>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>(4) Check that there is equal clearance around uplock actuator (11).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>(5) Fully retract gear. Lower gear by means of emergency system (see Paragraph 55) and check uplock actuator (11) emergency down line for leaks with 10 342 kPa (1500 psi) hydraulic pressure applied. Correct any leak.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>(6) Reconnect leg door (see Paragraph 17).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>m. On satisfactory completion of checks and repositioning of shuttle valves to their normal position (see Paragraph 55), install ground safety locking pins, disconnect ground power, lower aircraft to ground (see C-12-114-000/MF-001) and remove jacking equipment.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>n. Ensure that all parts removed or disturbed during the course of these operations are locked and, where applicable, in safety.</instruction>
      </step>
    </instructions>
  </module>
</data:assembly>
