<course> 
  <name>Main Landing Gear</name>
  <module name="Removal">
    <figure path="6-4-1.jpg"/>
    <instructions>
      <step>
        <instruction>a. Jack and steady aircraft (see C-12-114-000/ MF-001).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step> 
        <instruction>b. Remove main wheel </instruction>
        <assemblyFile>mainLandingGearWheel.xml"</assemblyFile>
      </step>
      <step> 
        <instruction>c. Remove brake assembly </instruction>
        <assemblyFile>brakeSystem.xml</assemblyFile>
      </step>
      <step> 
        <instruction>d. Connect ground power to aircraft. Open main wheel doors by operating hydraulic hand pump with ground servicing switch in port main gear bay selected to OPEN.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step> 
        <instruction>e. Disconnect weight switch lead at quickdisconnect in wheel well.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step> 
        <instruction>f. Disconnect brake line (9) at top of leg. Cap open ends and place tag in cockpit that brakes are not to be operated.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step> 
        <instruction> g. Remove cotter pin, nut and washer, and release actuator (6) from leg pin (7). Secure actuator clear of leg and, with thrust washer (8) located on pin (7), temporarily install washer and nut.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step> 
        <instruction>h. Disconnect leg door from leg by removing cotter pin, washer and pin (16).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step> 
        <instruction>i. Disconnect side stay (12) from leg by removing cotter pin, nut, washer and bolt (13). Secure side stay clear of leg.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step> 
        <instruction>j. Remove nut, washer, spacer and bolt (10) from rear pivot pin (11), and cotter pin, nut, retainer plate (5), guide washer (4) and special bolt (1) from forward pivot pin (3).</instruction>
        <warning>Visually inspect pivot pin (3) for cracks or damage.</warning>
        <note>If brake assembly has not been removed (see Step c), handle and position leg with care to avoid damage to brake assembly.</note>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>k. With leg supported, withdraw pivot pins (3 and 11) using special tools (see C-12-114000/MF-001, Figure 1-5, Item 36) and remove special washer (2). Slide gear inwards, turn gear and remove from aircraft.</instruction>
      </step>
    </instructions>
  </module>
  <module name="Installation">
    <instructions>
      <step>
        <instruction>a. Offer up and align gear with Unibal bearing and mounting plate bush.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>b. With special washer (2) located with bevelled edge towards Unibal (see Figure 6-4-14), install forward (3) and rear (11) pivot pins, using special tools (see C-12-114-000/ MF-001, Figure 1-5, Item 36).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>c. Install bolt (10), spacer (under bolt head), washer and nut on rear pivot pin (11), and special bolt (1), guide washer (4), retainer plate (5), nut and cotter pin on forward pivot pin (3), torquing nuts to values detailed in Figure 6-4-14.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>d. Connect side stay (12) to leg with bolt (13), washer, nut and cotter pin.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>e. Connect brake line (9) to connection at top of leg.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>f. Release air from leg (see C-12-114-000/ MF-001).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>g. Install and adjust weight switch (14). Clip lead of switch to clipping positions on leg and to retainer plate (5). Connect weight switch lead at quick-disconnect in wheel well. On completion of switch adjustment, recharge leg (see C-12-114-000/MF-001).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>h. Connect actuator (6) to pin (7) with plain washer, nut and cotter pin, and with thrust washer (8) installed at inner face with its chamfered side towards gear. Adjust actuator.</instruction>
        <assemblyFile>mainLandingGearActuator.xml</assemblyFile>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>i. If applicable, install brake assembly.</instruction>
        <assemblyFile>brakeSystem.xml</assemblyFile>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>j. If applicable, install main wheel.</instruction>
        <assemblyFile>mainLandingGearWheel.xml</assemblyFile>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>k. Bleed and operate the brakes.</instruction>
        <assemblyFile>bleedingAndFunctionalTest.xml</assemblyFile>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>l. Install ground safety locking pins to nose gear and serviceable main gear.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>m. Prepare to operate gear being serviced (see Paragraph 55).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>o. With 10 342 kPa (1500 psi) hydraulic pressure applied, check that gap at over-centre knuckle joint of side stay is from 0.051 to 0.254 mm (0.002 to 0.010 in.) when an upward force of 44.5 newtons (10 lb) is applied to joint. Adjustment to obtain gap requirement may be carried out as follows:</instruction>
        <note>If tight bearings give faulty readings when a 10 lb load is applied to the knuckle joint, loosen nuts securing the lower side stay assembly to allow the inner race of the bearing to turn on the bolts. Recheck as in Step o (7) and retorque the nuts.</note>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>p. Repeat Step n with 10 342 kPa (1500 psi) hydraulic pressure applied.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>q. Place gear control lever to UP and slowly retract gear. Check that gear retracts smoothly, with no binding, and that there is clearance between piping and moving parts. Clearance between gear and structure, etc, shall be at least 2.54 mm (0.100 in.). Check that there is at least 19.05 mm (3/4 in.) radial clearance around tire.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>r. Check that uplock engages correctly and that alignment meets requirements of Paragraph 8. Check that, when hydraulic pressure is released, uplock retains gear in retracted position.</instruction>
        <warning>To obtain the required clearance of at least 0.508 mm (0.020 in.) between the door connecting link and the brake bleed valve when the leg is compressed, it is essential that the cutouts in the fork pivot are towards the brake bleed valve as shown in Figure 6-4-8.</warning>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>s. Lower gear. Connect link of leg door to leg with pin (16), washer and cotter pin.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>t. Remove ground safety locking pins from other two gears.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>u. Operate the landing gear. Check that doors of gear being serviced close correctly, flush with skin. Check that clearances are correct (see Paragraphs 14 and 17) and that latching mechanism functions correctly to lock leg door.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>v. Operate gear several times and check that operating pressures and times are within stipulated limits (see Paragraph 55).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>w. Check that all components removed or disturbed during the foregoing operations are correctly locked and, where applicable, in safety.</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>x. Remove ground power. Install ground safety locking pins. Lower aircraft to ground and remove jacking equipment (see C-12-114000/MF-001).</instruction>
      </step>
      <step>
        <instruction>y. Check that tire and leg are correctly charged (see C-12-114-000/MF-001).</instruction>
      </step>
    </instructions>
  </module>
</course>
